Guide to the Shepard Kurnit papers, 1978-1983 and undated RL.11682
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Shepard Kurnit papers
1978-1983 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Kurnit, Shepard
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11682
4.0 Linear Feet
Advertising executive and market researcher with several agencies, including his own, in New York. Collection includes correspondence, research data printouts, photo- and storyboards of advertisements submitted by various agencies, videotapes and film reels that primarily document Kurnit's Television Advertising Perception (TAP) research project, that sought to map television and radio audience perceptions and readership of commercials against advertising agencies' creative expectations. Participant agencies include BBDO; Compton; Dancer Fitzgerald Sample; Della Femina Travisano; Foote Cone & Belding; Manoff Geer Gross; SSC&B; and Tracy Locke; and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Research Test Data; Audiovisual Materials.
Biographical / Historical
Advertising executive and market researcher with several agencies, including his own, in New York.
Born 1924, New York; Parsons School of Design 1941-1942; U.S. Army Air Force 1943-1945; Sterling Advertising 1945; Harry Serwer Advertising 1945-1957; C.J. Herrick Associates 1947-1949; Diamond Barnett Advertising 1949; founded Kurnit Associates 1950-1954; President, Kurnit Geller Associates 1954-1956; Executive Vice President, Calet Hirsch Kurnit & Spector (formerly Delahanty Kurnit & Geller/DKG Advertising) 1956-1981 (Chairman 1981-1983); Chairman, Ephron Raboy Tsao & Kurnit 1983-1986; founded Kurnit & Partners 1986; died 2001.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Shepard Kurnit papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
American Association of Advertising Agencies records
Charles McKinney papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Information Center records
J. Walter Thompson Company. Ronald B. Kaatz papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department records
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Research Department records
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, research data printouts, photo- and storyboards of advertisements submitted by various agencies, videotapes and film reels that primarily document Kurnit's Television Advertising Perception (TAP) research project, that sought to map television and radio audience perceptions and readership of commercials against advertising agencies' creative expectations. Participant agencies include BBDO; Compton; Dancer Fitzgerald Sample; Della Femina Travisano; Foote Cone & Belding; Manoff Geer Gross; SSC&B; and Tracy Locke; and Young & Rubicam. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Television advertising; Television advertising -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; Advertising -- Research; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc.; Compton Advertising, inc. -- History; Young & Rubicam
- General Files, 1978-1983 and undated; 1
  - Correspondence--Agencies and unions, 1978-1979; 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Notes, clippings, etc., 1983 and undated (Box 2)
  - Photoboards, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Compton, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Dancer Fitzgerald Sample, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Foote Cone & Belding, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Lee, King & Partners, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Manoff Geers Gross, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--SSC&B, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Spreadsheets, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Tracy-Locke, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Photoboards--Young & Rubicam, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Print material--Communique (Advertising Club of Louisville), 1979 (Box 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Features article announcing Kurnit speech at club meeting
  - Radio presentation, Anchorage, approximately 1979 (Box 2)
  - Reel 2 data sheets, undated (Box 1)
  - Reel 3 data sheets, undated (Box 1)
  - TAP (Television Audience Perception)--Book project, 1981 (Box 1)
    Television Advertising Perception (TAP) was a research project designed to determine whether consumers view advertisements in the same way as advertising professionals. Television commercials from 27 agencies were used with a questionnaire asking participants to rate the commercials on a scale in terms of "creative" and "convincing."
  - TAP (Television Audience Perception)--Description and notes, undated (Box 1)
- Research Test Data, 1980; 2
  - Breakouts by type, group, product, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - By agency, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Demographics of judges, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Products ranked by total creative mean score, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - QUBE on-air responses, Columbus, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
    QUBE (1977-1984) was an experimental, interactive cable television system launched in Columbus, Ohio.
  - Ranked by "convincing" mean score, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Ranked by "creative" mean score, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Reel 1, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Reel 2, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Reel 3, approximately 1980 (Box 3)
  - Reel 4, approximately 1980 (Box 4)
  - Reel 5, approximately 1980 (Box 4)
  - Shepard's master set, approximately 1980 (Box 4)
  - Testing site data, approximately 1980 (Box 4)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1978-1980 and undated; 3
  - Participating Agencies 1, 1978 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-001)
    Della Femina, Travisano +; Dancer Fitzerald Sample; Young & Rubicam; Norman Craig & Kummel; Foote Cone & Belding; BBDO; Case & McGrath; Benton & Bowles; Waring & LaRosa; Kenyon & Eckhardt
  - Participating Agencies 2, 1978 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-002)
    SSC& B; Ted Bates; Doyle Dane Bernbach; Compton; Campbell-Ewald; NW Ayer ABH International; McCaffree-McCall; Scali McCabe & Sloves; DKG; Ally & Gargano
  - QUBE reel, 1980 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-003)
  - Selections for Wall Street Journal (Bill Abrams), 1980 (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-004)
    Includes Bounty; Bolt; Baby Ruth; 5th Avenue Bar; Palmolive dishwashing; Ajax dishwashing; Guestware disposa ble plate; Chevrolet truck; Sunsensor; Polaroid One Step; Jello Pudding; Ford corporate; Lipton tea; Wheaties; Dunkin Donuts; Winchell's; Tonka; Fisher Price; AMF; Funk & Wagnalls; American Tourister; Dr. Scholl's; MGA-TV; Climatrol; Federal Express; AAMCO; Hertz; Avis; Foster Farms; Mrs. Pauls; Whataburger; Krystal Fried Chicken; Diet Pepsi; Muriel cigar; Aviance; Charlie; Cie; Chanel #5; Desitin; Johnson & Johnson Baby Shampoo; Fiat; Mercury Monarch; AMC Concord
  - Television Audience Perception reel 1, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-005)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 2, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-006)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 3, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-007)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 4, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-008)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 5, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-009)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 5, undated (Box AV1, Video-cassette RL11682-Umatic-010)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 1, undated (Reel 1, Film-reel RL11682-F16-001)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 2, undated (Reel 2, Film-reel RL11682-F16-002)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 3, undated (Reel 3, Film-reel RL11682-F16-003)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 4, undated (Reel 4, Film-reel RL11682-F16-004)
  - Television Audience Perception reel 5, undated (Reel 5, Film-reel RL11682-F16-005)